welcome to the second-in-command podcast
produced by the CEO Oh Alliance and
brought to you by its founder Cameron
Herold in the second-in-command podcast
we talked to top CEOs who share the
insights strategies and tactics that
made them the chief behind the chief and
now here's your host
Cameron Harold Vivian Ford is the senior
vice president of operations at comma
dot AI based in San Diego most new cars
on the road today are built with
features designed to assist with driving
but failed to deliver commas open source
software open pilot enables your car to
steer accelerate and brake automatically
in its lane it's easy to install and
trusted by thousands of drivers with
over 10,000 miles
vivianne previously worked at East WA
communications for one year back when it
was six people in a garage in San
Francisco so Vivien I am really looking
forward to hearing what you're working
on and welcome to the second grand
podcast so tell us just a little bit
more about comments that we understand
kind of where where these devices are
being installed or how they're being
installed in cars what kind of cars are
we installing them in because I'm
especially excited about autonomous
vehicles yeah totally so basically
Thomas sells a hardware development kit
that works on existing basically 2016
and newer Honda's Toyota's Subarus whole
range of supported cars we saw this
hardware that runs our open source
software so back in 2017 the open
sourced this thing called open pilot
which is essentially autopilot for
existing vehicles so a driver assistance
system that takes you on the highway and
will on the highway will drive you 90
percent of the time and then when you're
doing you know back road driving you
obviously take over and so we have
thousands of cars driving with both the
the comma E on and open
and we have over 10 million miles of
driving data collected and our yeah just
working on upping that number and
getting more and more compatible cars
and more people with the system in their
car unbelievable ok so this is a
third-party software then are you
starting to license this software did
any of the car companies are you just
selling this as the connector market
addition to vehicles so so the software
yes the software is under MIT license so
we open-source this on github if someone
wanted to go and build a system that ran
the software and then sell that system
they'd be completely entitled to we are
we basically just sell to whoever wants
to buy it if Ford wanted to buy you know
a hundred common ions you know that the
hardware and install it in their
vehicles they could go ahead and do that
you know we don't have a business
development department we have we have a
website with an order now button and we
will fulfill on Mondays and Thursdays
Wow ok so I I was 10 years ago I wrote
in the first Google experimental car at
Ted I was at the main TED Conference
sitting in the audience and someone from
Google came out and talked about this
vehicle and then they showed a video and
you know I'm sitting beside Jeff Bezos
Bill Gates is in the audience and
they're talking about this car that none
of us had seen I don't think very many
had even heard about it 10 years ago and
then the the person who's doing the
demonstration said by the way if you
want to drive in it it's out this door
on the parking lot and 1800 people stood
up and went running and I got to drive
it and I have a video on my laptop of me
driving in this Prius 10 years ago with
Mort Matt Groening the founder of The
Simpsons was beside me in the vehicle
and we drove on a test track 10 years
ago at 45 miles an hour and I was just
going holy like this thing is
extraordinary
yeah and I've since owned to Teslas I've
been driving them now for years how
how complex I got so so MIT labs
developed the software and then you guys
are third-party licensing it or did you
develop my choice yeah we developed the
software it's under MIT license but we
did develop a software and so yeah
basically we you know we maintain the
software the beauty of having open
source software is that one you get a
community that can contribute to it so
there's so many you know there's so many
makes and models out there that are a
little different and how they run
and so when you community member that
wants this to be supported for their car
and if they go through the effort to you
know send a pull request to have their
car supported and merged with you know
the next version of open pilot like
that's fantastic you're building
community of people that are you know
actively working to basically like it to
you know to push forward the technology
and also a beautiful thing about the
open-source code is that code is you
know anyone can if anyone's concerned
with the code they can go and read
through it they can you know if there's
safety concerns or whatever to some
extent code is speech so they can go
ahead and have their you know have a
look at everything we do and decide for
themselves if this is something they
want to put in their car instead of
getting into you know like a I don't
know a Honda Civic with the lane keep
assist system and having really little
idea of how it works and just kind of
you know trust and get and engaging it
and seeing it for yourself you know how
it works on the road and so why am I
scared of this why is this got me work
with the open-source idea that somebody
can just download this and put it into
their car why is that scaring the hell
out of me when I went again I've been
you know I drove my Tesla Model 3 from
Scottsdale to Vancouver and let it drive
2000 or the 2200 miles on its own but
this scares me for some reason what am I
missing
I think there's a couple of reasons that
these is scary and the first one is that
any time there's a autonomous vehicle
accident like it is so publicized it's
publicized until people can just you
know get
single blast click on their story
possible so we have so so many ideas in
our head that like these systems aren't
safe or you know oh but did you see that
you know this auto pilot accident caused
this issue whereas it's like sure along
with that article what if we also
publicize how many people die just by
driving a regular car that sertoli yeah
I think there's that level that's a
little alarming the open source code I
think also scares people because I don't
want to say that any of like the worst
like responsibility is the hardware to
place in this situation but Minh dove
like hey take a look at our code if you
like our code then maybe you'll you know
want to explore and experiment with it
and and and see how it runs with your
Honda Civic and so there's like an
active active like exploration phase
that the driver is is using because
they're downloading this code from the
internet and they're they're trying it
in their vehicle as opposed to kind of a
black box delivery of you know Tesla
autopilot here you are take a drive but
we're like where are they testing this
oh they're downloading the software and
they're just throwing it in their car
and they're going for a drive around
Scottsdale sure yeah I mean we have we
have millions of miles of driving data
from this we have hundreds of YouTube
videos of people driving around with the
system so well where are they testing it
like they're you know it's it's better
testing almost than any other
self-driving car companies product
because they don't even have a product
really you know like there's only so
many I mean part of the big issue too is
like there's so many edge cases with
drivings that it's impossible to to hand
code all of the edge cases of driving
George I think it like Elon Musk had a
line when we first came out with the
system and he was like you know sure 99%
of this is easy it's the one percent
that's really hard right but when you
try to capture all of the edge cases
like way mo with like I don't know what
their fleet is let's say their fleets
like a hundred cars or whatever
but that's still just that's not gonna
get you all of the edge cases and so
when you're just relying and depending
on you know all of the the all of the
data from your own cars as opposed to
kind of like decentralizing the data
consumption and getting data from people
all over the world you know all of a
sudden you have a much more like fully
packaged kind of you know data
exploration to go whether were there a
lot of legal hurdles in getting launched
or getting the product out the door
certainly so yeah I mean we we got a
letter from the National Highway
Transportation Safety Authority back in
2016 and so I yes so so we we actually I
think I think the open source in 2016
who knows the years are all the same but
regardless they they were concerned we
had announced at TechCrunch that we were
selling this product with open pilot on
the product and that this product was
going to drive your car I mean it was a
lot of hype the product can't drive you
know nothing can drive your car you
still can't sit in a self-driving car
everything driver assistance system
still level two and so there was
definitely you know I think similar when
you ask why am I scared of this there's
just a lack of information around a lot
of this stuff and so a big thing with
open sourcing it's like how do we show
the information how do we you know how
do we just like yeah explain like what's
going on and and and publish more of the
information publish more of the data we
definitely tried to do this with like
more medium posts we've tried to publish
more you know like this is how we're
using the data this is how we're trying
we're being compliant with NHTSA's
requests they basically sent a list of
17 questions I think was about 17 and
they were totally reasonable they were
totally reasonable questions asking us
you know like what what is this product
what is it doing how can you guarantee
certain aspects about the product and
but apart from that I think the I think
like the trend of the general
self-driving space is moving more
towards like not even away from
regulation but like when you have you
know lame-o come out and announce that
they like hyped it up a little too much
for the first X years that they've been
you know working on self-driving cars or
you have all these companies that are
slowly realizing like this problem is
actually really difficult like not that
regulation catches up but it just the
the problem slows down that the pace you
think it'll be solved slows down and
that reassures people automatically yeah
I think it's also the people are getting
more and more comfortable with it now
we're just we're not hearing about the
accidents constantly we have heard the
arguments now that there's other cars
that are crashing we're not hearing
about those so I think we're just
getting more and more comfortable with
the idea and then we're also you know
four years ago it was just weird or five
years ago was weird hearing a Tesla
creep up behind you and now it's like oh
you you almost can hear them now which
is so bizarre right we could never hear
them before and now we can hear them
which is really strange so how did you
get involved in the company so the
founder I lived in this house called the
crypto castle in San Francisco very San
Francisco it was basically a three-story
townhouse in downtown San Francisco with
a bunch of people who were interested in
Bitcoin and cryptocurrencies and George
the founder moved into the basement of
this house he was basically looking to
start his own self-driving car start up
and needed a basement where he could
pack away a car and so I'm and became
friends he I like just lived and saw him
develop this company for the first like
seven or eight months and then in about
a year later three and a half years ago
he was looking for an Operations person
and I went up to him and I said he
should hire me and definitely took some
convincing
um and yeah about two weeks later I
think I was offered the job and I took
it with very little operations
experience that's really cool okay so
you guys got involved he saw it in the
earliest sort of early stages and then
you went to and you did you launched it
disrupt in New York yeah yeah so I mean
yes that was 2016 13 early stages we we
had done a Bloomberg article in 2015
which launched I think that it was like
really the first of first unofficial
official launch of just comma as a
company and people were intrigued to see
what he was up to what he was doing and
then in at TechCrunch we announced this
whole you know shebang of a product kind
of trying to fall into the hype of
self-driving cars before you quickly
realized that all of that is dangerous
to fall into and then we open sourced so
yeah correct myself we open sourced the
software in 2016 we had no hardware we
had and we had hardware be an
open-source the hardware required to run
on the software but we weren't selling
it and then we had a community of people
just like building out this harder and
and and working on the product and then
we if we launched the comedy on the
hardware that supports open pilot if if
people want it also we launched it was a
dash cam so you know for people that
came development kit launched that in
2017 and kind of have consistently been
you know updating with with new versions
of both Eon and open pilot how are you
funded so through a 16 ca-16 zeal we
were still serious seed a 16 z led our
to our two rounds yeah we did two series
seeds how much have you raised so far
the 8.1 mountain
that's pretty substantial for a seed yes
it was to seed so the first seed was 3.1
million the second seed was 5 million we
have we have revenue um we have revenue
and we keep our power we keep operations
very very lean we're team of 13 12 or 13
you know it's yeah if the real goal has
been how do we become profitable which
is not a question that startups asked
themselves but I think it was you know
kind of a it was important to be like if
this is gonna be sustainable how can we
make money along the way as opposed to
just blowing through millions and
millions of dollars to technology that
you can't even ship you know yeah yeah I
led I I was brought in as a coach for
the team at HootSuite about four or five
years ago and I led their strategic
planning retreat and I pushed them to
consider profitability as a way to scale
instead of more equity in debt financing
and they decided to go for it and I'm
like I don't understand why people don't
like it's so simple to actually build a
real company if you decide to and you
have what any more control so that is
that is that is your focus then yeah and
what you said was build a real company
that's exactly what we do and we yeah
it's it's way more control it's also
just the easiest we didn't know that
you're actually adding value to the
world is you know are you - yeah if
people are buying it you're making money
off of it and it keeps you lean and
keeps you smart and scrappy it's so
amazing when we think when whatsapp sold
for like 1.4 billion they only had 50
employees yeah you know so you're on the
same trajectory so I love that that he
was working with getting some
early-stage free PR Ezra well I wrote a
book about a year ago called free PR and
it talks about how to leverage free
publicity for your brand and how to
generate it in-house instead of using a
PR firm yeah and then how do I kind of
because you guys have got some huge
upside clearly with PR I'm sure as well
yeah totally well also yeah I mean I so
George our president the founder he
comes he's he comes from like a hacking
background so people have like followed
his you know what he's been up to and
what his projects have been throughout
and so that was helpful too and also
it's like an underdog story that first
of all Silicon Valley loves
and the people in fiscal love where it's
like you know this one guy you know puts
together some self-driving car that like
you know competes against Tesla's and
whether or not it's true whether or not
you know how much hype you want to have
if you get a story like that to start
off your company people are gonna be
excited to see where it's at
I got missed out on the seed round at
Tesla by not putting $5,000 deposit down
on the original Roadster 15 15 16 years
ago yeah I was a bad bad call I also
told the founder of uber it was a stupid
idea when we heard him deciding before
he launched I was took him to Burning
Man and he was explaining it to me I'm
like this is before he hired Travis so
yeah I think you're onto something if I
told you it's a bad idea go all-in
though as well because okay so I know
how you got involved in the business and
when you started dealing with the whole
open source what can you teach us about
that what's been that would have been
the I guess what are the hassles would
have been the pitfalls and they the
struggles with the whole open source
side of the business
I mean honestly there are not many I
mean
the beauty of being an open-source
business is that it forces you to like
you're not you're not going to just
open-source your software and then be
very secretive about everything else you
do you're gonna be an open company it's
gonna approach what you do with an open
mindset and so kind of a default mindset
of kamma is like publicise what's
happening be honest about what's
happening you know like yeah there's
nothing we don't want to have things to
hide because if you have secrecy you
probably don't have anything at all is
the idea and so I think that that's
definitely a just like a positive a very
positive reinforcement of what
open-source does for me like from a
personal perspective I had come
I joined comma from like a tech PR firm
that was very much like embargoed until
this date don't you dare break that you
know and so I enter into this world of
comma where all of these people are deep
you know deeply admire the open-source
community and you you can't help but get
stressed about potential competitors
that decide to you know use this or get
a leg up on whatever they're doing but
then you really said that's exactly the
point where like if you do open-source
this and you do give even you know even
like people who aren't necessarily
direct competitors but if this
information is out there in the world
then everyone already has a plus-one to
having this information we just like
help you know and also like if if a
competitor comes along and builds a
better hardware system that's gonna run
this system but it will then you better
work your ass off to make sure that
that's not the case and that your system
is always promising you know the the
better experience for users so
definitely for me initially it was kind
of like a jolt of a different way of
thinking that's cool so you said you
came in and you didn't have any
operations experience so how did you how
have you learned it
I mean on the job yeah yeah I think the
the thing I quickly realized was that
operations
you don't want glory in operations you
want to be like as behind-the-scenes as
possible because it means the company's
being run and people aren't realizing
that something's an issue if that you
know you don't want there to be issues
which was a very interesting just just a
different approach of like okay how do I
you know how do I go about this how do i
how do I make sure that the things that
are happening are happening in a way
that that people don't like people can
do their job and thankfully like comma
grew with me
you know comma when I joined comma was I
think we had ten or eleven people
because we had interns and those interns
left so we were like down to six at one
point so six person company if you've
never done operations before you can
learn and you can like manage quickly
and because common has scaled that like
a very I think like appropriate rate
it's been a good a good way of like
learning and yeah I mean when you're in
San Francisco every other person does
operations to some extent right
Moses yeah how about attracting talent I
mean the Bay Area's got to be one of the
most competitive areas for tech talent
for sure and for even for the Ontario
students so how are you attracting
talent yeah so this was very interesting
and and one of the reasons we actually
moved to San Diego oh right yeah you're
in San Diego now too
you've done San Diego yeah I think
initially I mean working at comma is
different than working at almost any
other company so already with just like
the open source factor you're gonna
attract people that are interested in
the open source community and that was
key so like number one way for us to
attract count talent was like through
get up pouring over people's kid hopes
making sure that you know like people
were already contributing to the open
source community people who are excited
about those projects are gonna be really
excited about you know open sourced your
consistent system so that was kind of a
helpful way also I think that so yeah it
is real
hard to you know when Google's gonna pay
a machine learning engineer hundreds of
thousands of dollars and you're trying
to keep your startup very lean and
you're not gonna offer that what you get
on the flip side though is people that
are in it because they really do believe
that this company is going to succeed
which is always the goal and so you know
you people who come in and take you know
you give a sliding scale of equity and
salary and people who take like you know
is the slowest salary and the highest
equity because always like a positive
you know reinforcement of where this
person thinks the company is going
moving to San Diego
so it was hard it's it's obviously super
hard to recruit it's obviously very hard
to attract talent and going to San Diego
one of the ideas was like okay maybe
we'll be able to attract talent more
easily qual comes here you know maybe
will be different than the thousands of
startups in the Bay Area that are all
trying to attract the same people that
played out so I Monica Lee we a lot of
our employees not a lot but a decent
amount now have come from our community
and so that's proven to be like more and
more the best way to get people is
people that are that find themselves in
the common community are already
interested and then if they you know
contributed really positively floating
the idea of joining a company it's like
an exciting next step so and also just
kind of realizing that San Diego is also
a more pleasant place to live I think
then the Bay Area barry smith says he
was amazing yes you news great it's
easier to attract people from you know
wherever in the u.s. to move to San
Diego than to move to San Francisco well
in San Diego's got a pretty good
technology sector as well a pretty good
entrepreneurial sector there's a lot of
biotech but you know also that that
helps because then we're we're not
biotech so we're different yeah I've got
a bunch of my for I've coached a lot of
companies and I've got a number of
different coaching clients that are in
San Diego and then a couple of our
members of our CEO or Alliance are in
San Diego as well it's just it's a great
great market so what are you guys
struggling with right now what are the
pain points
I think the main pain point is like what
what do you want your company to look
like you know we built this company and
you were you you're working towards
profitability so this is the old this is
for now the ultimate goal you know like
in the immediate future but what kind of
a company do you scale into what kind of
company do you become how do you
decentralize the responsibilities of the
company so you don't have like one
single point of failure being your CEO
or whatever how do you you know how do
you work on I guess at the core of it
like it's our product in the company we
talk about a lot stability so stability
on the product and stability in the
company and how do you build something
that will outlast everyone that is
currently at this company you know those
kind of thoughts that you have when you
yeah if you're profitable you can
self-sustained for hopefully a very very
long time and then what does that look
like
how are you kind of giving the vision to
your team right now how are you
articulating it or getting them aligned
and inspired and then how do you also
keep a group of people super excited
when they're coming on for equity and
the company's seemingly moving towards a
profitability focus does that distract
them at all I mean in and by all rights
they should be focused on profitability
anyway but if it's builder busts that's
a different goal so how do you keep
people incentive is an interesting less
incentive eyes and more a more aligned
more aligned and inspired you know it's
the vision yeah they're not just trying
to focus on an exit I think what helps
is having an actual user base so we have
like a community discord and a lot of
our users are on that discord and a lot
of our employees are on that discord
talking fusers you know like having beta
programs and stuff like that that house
because you literally see what you are
doing affecting people that you were
talking being a 13-person company what
you work on has a big impact you know
you're not working on like a product
project with IP
bounine have that be scrapped like if
you don't do something it's obvious and
it hurts you know it hurts the company
so I think that alignment like will come
naturally just people seeing you know
what their work has and then in terms of
like the profitability equity think I
don't even think it's directly related
to comma when people hear that I think
it's more of a realization of like the
state of feces in the state of San
Francisco Silicon Valley or like that
money will dry up the money that they're
just handing out to companies will dry
up so if you do want to succeed if you
do want to win at self-driving cars and
solve self-driving cars what better way
than to create a profitable company that
doesn't die on these investors and I
think that mindset just helps in general
you know people get on board with with
yeah putting profit first can you and I
know that you're still privately held
and still see drowned can you can you
disclose some numbers to us in terms of
users and revenue numbers at all or did
you to keep that stuff private still so
we had I think was around 160 grand in
revenue um and you know we spend at a
rate of about you know about probably
180 grand a month is our burn rate so
you know close to close to getting those
two numbers very aligned which is yeah
which would be great and ideally we
don't need to raise money again you know
ideally we are profitable early next
year and and can continue sailing how
are you getting the word out right now
how are you guys getting the the buzz is
it PR is it just your community is that
it's yeah it's community it's it's
really the community we don't really
have any I don't have anyone here that
does marketing we don't really have
anyone here that isn't an engineer apart
from like myself I do operations that's
kind of engineering some sourcebook in
some way but we don't have marketing
program we don't have visit up
departments so it's really the community
it's really like you know
someone posted YouTube video and then it
gets on reddit or something like that
you know like where how are those sales
coming we also have you know it's not I
mean it's not like the simplest thing
when you purchase the the Aeon dev kit
you know it's still you're like is my
car supported you have all these
questions so there's still a lot of
low-hanging fruit of the people that
come to our website how can you know how
can we make it super clear for them if
they want to purchase it what are they
purchasing what they need to do and so
yeah but but definitely like getting
more people to the site is isn't is of
course a goal I think we're still just
focusing on like the people who do come
to site how can we make sure that it's
abundantly clear what what they could be
buying or not this is not expensive this
is six hundred bucks yeah it's
ridiculous I think by the way I think
the autonomous vehicles will be the
cause of the next baby boom you guys can
quote me on that you can put that in all
of your PR for real right you think
about like L people driving in LA
traffic for an hour what are you gonna
be doing you're not gonna be hanging out
in the front seat you're gonna hop in
the back and that would be then I'll be
like y'all's all commute to work like
people know what I don't want to work
from home anymore I want to commute do
you do you run on a remote team or do
you all run out of the office together
one guy whose remote but he was with us
for two years so he knew very well how
the company worked but really try to be
everyone in the office just helps so
much more with you know and also like I
joke that we don't really have any
meetings we have one meeting a week on
Monday mornings for it you know just to
sync up what's happening but I kind of
joke that like everything is a media
comment just in the sense that like you
know at lunch when you miss a
conversation you're missing a lot you
know to be really at all times people
are talking about their projects and
like what's the hold up and you know so
yeah it's just it's pretty important to
be yeah I think it's I think it's
critical in the early stage for sure of
a business to actually have that cooler
time and lunchtime and just kind of
interacting that that beta transfer is
amazing what happens there so how about
yourself and what
working on your skills right now is the
second-in-command so I run operations
here so basically everything everything
non-technical so I do you know yeah
operations recruiting accounting legal
HR you know yeah all of that kind of
stuff right now personally I'm working
on so we have some exciting things
coming next year that we're working on
and recruiting in this area recruiting
in San Diego understanding like how do
we yeah how do we build out teams here
you know reaching out to people in the
US and abroad
um and kind of all the things that come
in operations you know if I were to give
you like a given day it would change
drastically from one day to the next
how about technology tools what tools do
you use or does the company use to to
scale to manage you so for operations um
I mean I I don't know exactly these are
the tools you're thinking but like I'm
such a big fan these adorable startups
in San Francisco like Augusto and zero
that are incredibly helpful and have
fantastic customer service support
because they like because they needs
because they want to be yeah I really I
have been like very almost pleasantly
happy that the startup world is a thing
even though it can be unbelievably
frustrating but you know when you're
trying to get corporate credit cards for
your employees from Wells Fargo and they
require everyone's social security
numbers and all of these things that are
such a headache beyond belief and that
makes everything feel super
uncomfortable to have to give to you
know some big bank and then you stumble
upon upon a complete
Drex that you literally just sign up
online and get you know corporate cards
mailed to you in like three days
I mean it's so like the convenience of
so many of these of these companies is
to me and I'm so happy with it because
otherwise it's such a pain in the butt
to that steel so yeah we you know so
Gusto's the HR Payroll software Xero is
the accounting software relaxes
corporate cards so we use you know use
those otherwise I think considering you
started out of the crypto Castle re do
you accept any cryptocurrency as payment
for your products we used to and then it
was such a pain in the butt taxes to
have to claim you know how it just
became so not worth it but we had so
back when we were definitely had this
open-source hardware called the common
Neo terrible a terrible neon green color
really we you know back in the early
days there was a company that was
building them and selling them I think
they were building them and selling them
for one Bitcoin which at the time was
probably $700 and then December 2017 you
know people know Bitcoin Rises to 17
grand so I hope that I forget Neo German
is their name I hope they they did well
with their Bitcoin except you know
except transactions I was telling I
gotta go back and look at the dates but
I think it was 2009 that I was telling
people on Facebook 9 or 10 I know I was
freakin early maybe it was not a maybe
was 2012 but it was really early I said
when it was when Bitcoin was $400 nice
that I was I was accepting Bitcoin as
payment for speaking events and for
coaching people like you need why would
you do that but I ran a digital currency
company 20 years ago I had Starwood
Hotels and Bose stereo and Avis
rent-a-car Hard Rock Cafe all paying me
with a digital currency instead of a US
dollar we sold the company in 2000 so
yeah that we had thirty thousand
businesses buying and selling using and
digital currency no it was called it was
called you barter calm we sold we sold
464 million butBut it was a real
business we had they were open to using
digital currencies oh yeah we'd start
with hotels we had great little swipe
cards you could actually use it some of
them using merchants their merchant
processing and it was just a bilateral
multilateral trade and it was it wasn't
back we met with guys at Goldman Sachs
and like wait so what's backing your
barter dollar and we went nothing and
they went oh my god you you print money
and we went yeah they're like you're
like a country and we're like yeah any
much we actually print our own currency
because we if we needed more money we
would just give ourselves a credit line
we'd go buy furniture for the office
with our own crypto
it was crazy so I've always believed
that I think there's a huge need for it
but I think one day it'll come back
around that you can start accepting it
again yeah yes certainly it'll it'll
yeah it's on the up and up despite how
people might feel about it so when
you're alene when you're lean start up
in a smaller team and you're focused on
profitability and not burning through
cash what are you trying to say no to um
it's a good question because if there's
a very fine line between like being too
strict with the cash and you know
therefore not having like where does
productivity and cash spend meet
perfectly so one thing that we did like
a big overhaul of was services you know
random services that you sign up for
that you forget that you're you know
signed up to and then you realize that
you know at the end of the year you
spent 15 plus grand on services like so
down on that also
I mean honestly a lot of you know a lot
of like a good amount of PR can be
ridiculously expensive if you don't know
how to you know either if you don't know
how to use ad spend correctly or you
know you can hire a lot of consultants
that a lot of times don't actually add
value and that are ridiculously
expensive so how do you you know what
can basically what can I do how much
would it cost if someone else did it and
what's the value if someone else does it
versus me doing it and I think most
people - because you know because it's a
small team it's faster for them to just
do most things on their own
instead of using you know another
service or whatever but also yeah a
13-person team in San Diego with you
know I mean we have competitive salaries
now that we're in San Diego but nesaf
definitely lasts you know you start to
yeah it starts to almost naturally be
more lean certainly naturally be more
lean on when your zero Cisco they kind
of have to be take a look by the way at
my book free PR I think you guys might
have a huge opportunity to leverage free
publicity in-house how to generate its
how when we built 1-800 GOT JUNK we
landed
five thousand two hundred stories by
ourselves with no PR firm and that was
that was prior to Facebook launching so
we had no social media platforms to
actually leverage our PR on that was all
individual uniques including Oprah so by
the way I should shout out 100 that jump
because you guys save just so many times
yeah we're out of a house in San
Francisco that stuff you know piles up
quickly
that was our he was our fifth franchisee
the guy who owns the Bay Area does 20
million just in San Francisco on junk
removal he's killing it alright last
question we've got if you were to go
back to your younger self just starting
out in your career what word of advice
would you give yourself that now you
know to be true but you wish you'd known
then
I would say at the end of the day at the
end of the day responsibility falls on
you which seems like an obvious thing to
say but if you are you know even if you
were managing someone and they mess up
that inevitably falls on you and the
second you think in that way you start
to think more like the company you start
to think in a much more productive way
to actually getting stuff done to
actually you know shipping out products
and yeah and and moving a company along
because it's it's not it's no longer
individually based so you know thinking
in the sense of you know what
responsibilities do I give how do I
trust that that person will get it done
and if they don't okay that's on me what
do I do yeah or what did you do wrong
that let them let that happen I think
that's amazing
Ben Ben Horowitz in in his book hard
thing about hard things talked about
kind of that level of introspection
that's really important for leaders that
often when we're firing somebody we're
like oh I'm glad they're gone they're
terrible at this they're terrible at
that it's like well you hired them yeah
exactly so how what was wrong with the
interviewing process what was wrong with
the recruiting process what was wrong
with the top grading or the reference
checks or the training program or the
leadership or like how did you let this
happen and when we take that level of
ownership and introspection is powerful
and also on top of that it doesn't
happen again because now it's like you
know traced back to this point when this
was the mistake as opposed like you know
let it go as oh it's their fault it's
gonna happen again
yeah that's awesome Vivian Ford thank
you so much for joining us really
appreciate you sharing everything you
guys are doing with comma and really
excited about what you're doing work for
autonomous vehicles thank you so much
for having me this was a lot of fun yeah
thanks for sharing
you've been listening to
second-in-command brought to you by CEO
Oh Alliance founder Cameron Harold if
you enjoyed this episode please be sure
to subscribe for more best practices
from industry leading CEOs visit CEO Oh
Alliance com
you